I'm a Romeo, after the 737 at Whiskey, monitor tower $1.365 here.
Number 4550, do you know how long it will be, or any...
We're just contacting this, but the airport was actually going through the weather,
has dropped down below the moon, so we're trying to work out what they want to do.
Number 4450, 6...
Why don't you make that right on Kilo, right on Alpha, I have the ramping you out the back.
It's a rod on Kilo, a rod on Alpha, and a bridge on the other back.
Yeah, the 667, we're going to run out Whiskey, you're going to actually be a Kilo.
Seniora, actually, a Kilo, and at Sierra, I'll follow the company 73 from the right,
it'll show the Yankee, it'll be about 20 minutes for internal facing.
United at 667, Kilo, Sierra, I'll follow the 737, hold short at 8.
United, 667.
That's 421-21, we're going to attack to the Alpha.
That's the Alpha, we're going to attack between the crowd, we're going to attack at 238,
we're going to attack for Charlie 74.
That's 238, we're going to attack the...
Take that right to our Bravo, we'll show the Alpha now.
Bravo short, Alpha, it's 9, United at 238.
We're going to 100, continue on tier, hold short at Yankee.
Tier 75, United at 1, T100.
The ground gets through 2, 2, Romeo, and so short at Alpha, Alpha, Alpha, 10.
Touch 10, bye.
Yeah, 2100, continue on Mike, short at Romeo, please.
Okay, Mike, short at Romeo, he's, I did 4100.
5, signature, taxi, first at pass.
635, North Grand, taxi to the Brewster pad, once you're there, call us our team three.
3, what's up there?
So we're just going to continue on Bravo, see your...
Bravo short at golf, please.
We've got restrictions and volume over no, just so you can probably be delayed about 10 to 15 minutes.
Thank you, guys.
Thank you for recording.
Where are you?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, what are you waiting for?
Waiting to pay back.
Just fast about at the project.
Can you make that left on Bravo there?
Short of, uh, short at Romeo, Lima.
We're on uniform.
Alright, just hold it there, let me know what they think.
Okay.
We've got a 238 truck, Bravo short of Alpha, so.
You know, 238, okay.
Your gate is occupied, it looks like, uh, call the ramp, and that's how long it's going to be.
You know, there's 21, 100, continue via Romeo and monitor tower with Davis, Lima.
Okay, we have Lima, and all the towers of the day, United 21, 100.
Big ground, United, uh, 238.
Sir, they're showing us open now, so continue via, um, Alpha, uh, 2-9 in Alpha.
Tryin' Alpha to negate United 238, thank you.
Sir, what's the delay for it for us?
Second?
Second, six, six, seven, just curious why they're 20 minutes away.
Oh, there's volume and restrictions over Newell, uh, from the, uh, center.
Yeah, that, uh, that company that's at the wrong way is, uh, also over Newell, and he had a time to work here, so I had a, we had to make him first.
No worries.
Two, Romeo, let's go short of Alpha, Alpha, 10.
She'll be super talk to you, no ground, proceed on, uh, wait for, uh, come see to go by, and then proceed on out.
For companies, go by and proceed out, so you have some super talk too.
Sound good, buddy, prepare 3673 on Charlie for 87.
Good 3673, no ground, turn right on, uh, Bravo, short of Echo, for now please.
For the short of Echo, prepare 3673.
So I make a Bravo, short of Delta Lima.
I've got a short of Delta Lima, I'll break your 3673.
Ground, hip, and super talk too, behind, united from right to left.
Ship, and super talk too, is that you at, uh, Romeo Echo?
Okay, firm.
Yeah, proceed on, Alpha now.
Look at that, proceed on, Alpha, yep, and super talk too.
And break your 3673, let's see, uh, Jeff.
Excuse me, let the Jeff blue and it still go by on Alpha, then proceed on it, uh, Delta Lima, Alpha, it's in the rain.
I'm out for the ramp, after Jeff blue, we're here at 3673.
Ground, good morning, at 1631, Bravo, short of Kilo, taxi, please.
At 1631, you're going to try to Wiski, taxi via Kilo, Romeo, and monitor tower, with it is Lima.
Kilo, Romeo, by our tower, we're leaving by United, 1631, thank you.
732, 6 heavy, continue, shred ahead on Romeo to Wiski.
635, 6 heavy, monitor tower, with it is Lima, good day.
We have the power tower for acceleration.
4ogram, out to 813, taxi to Lima.
Mountain 8, 3, 13, north ground, runway 2, try to Wiski, taxi via Bravo, and Romeo.
Bravo, Romeo, thanks to right Wiski.
52473, Bravo, short of Kilo, taxi, Lima.
2473, north ground, Wiski, taxi via Kilo, Romeo, monitor tower.
Kilo, Romeo, monitor tower, 2, 2, red of Wiski.
1493, 1, 3, 4396, Bravo, short of Kilo, with Lima.
1496, north ground, Wiski, try to Wiski, follow United, and monitor tower, with it is Lima.
We're following United, monitor tower, with Lima, 4396.
44500, Bravo, Wiski, Lila, with Lima.
44500, 21, 2, try to Wiski, follow a company.
We're at little two balls coming in, we'll work 4500.
We're going to get A&I 1323 Romeo Golf with...
A&I 1323, no account. We've got a whiskey, tax, TV, a Juliet, then whole short of Romeo.
A&I short of Romeo, two right with A&I 1323.
A&I 2313, hold short of Kilo.
Short Kilo, A&I 313.
A&I 313.
Number 4500, monitor tower with Aida's Lima.
4500, monitor tower.
United 667, turn right on Yankee.
And at Romeo, you're going to follow the second RJ, monitor tower.
All right, Yankee, Romeo, follow the second RJ, forward to tower.
I have six, six, seven.
Four, call.
Okay.
A&I 1323.
A&I 3310, only two, try to wish, key, tax, TV, a Bravo, and Romeo.
This is where the whiskey's got a Romeo matinee.
Four, in the third, 44, 56, right here in the fourth, sure.
Yeah, okay, we're ready.
Number 4456, Romeo, we've got a whiskey, tax, TV, a whiskey, and whole short of Chiara.
Right, just a right with Chi, tax, TV, a whiskey, whole short of Chiara in the third, 44, 56.
2313, continue on Romeo, follow United at Yankee.
And monitor tower with Aida's Lima.
Romeo, follow United, and you're going to follow the three, first of all.
Number 4456, continue with key, and have Romeo going to wave on follow the second Caravan,
and then monitor tower with Aida's Lima.
Okay, whiskey, continue, I'll show Romeo, and he will be following the second Caravan.
We'll go on, we'll go on.
We'll move on.
He outboxed the era, and we'll show the Julia.
If you're right with the outfit here, we'll show the Julia in American 1603.
Not the 83-10 Monison Tower with A.T.L.E.M.
United 1323, you're going to follow this caravan from the right, and then follow an R.G. at Whiskey.
I follow the caravan from the right, and then I whiskey upon R.J. United 1623.
1323 Monison Tower with A.T.L.E.M.
I would have to tell you that.
This is very good.
CBS 208 heavy information, lame on Zulu 4, ready for taxi.
Just Zulu Avenue, ground with two tracks from Whiskey, taxi, Zulu uniform, Whiskey, and cross only one one.
Two rails on Whiskey, Zulu 4, uniform, Whiskey, Zulu uniform Whiskey, cross only one one.
CBS 208 heavy.
Market 1603, continue VFC, Iraq, T.L. Romeo.
A little Romeo, American 1603.
Alpha 8.
Who's developing?
American 1337, which is 40.
American 1370, good morning, run with two tracks from Whiskey, taxi, Bravo, and Romeo.
A runway 2-2, right at Whiskey, taxi, Charlie Bravo, Romeo.
Correct?
Romeo for two tracks from Whiskey.
Bravo, Romeo, two tracks from Whiskey, American 1370.
American 1603, monitor tower.
Camera 1603.
UPS 208 heavy at Romeo.
Followed the first American.
Then monitored tower with David Lima.
For the first American follow-around, monitor tower with my radio cable, T.M.
Gary.
Internet in 1437, plus November parking, Alpha 19.
Internet 1437, neuro ground, taxi, Alpha 10 to the ring.
This is where I am.
1437.
Good morning, United.
577, D.E., going to run with Alpha.
United 570, no ground, taxi, Alpha 10 to the ring.
We're at 957.
We've got 3695, clarinet, golf gate, is open and available for Romeo Bell factory.
We've got 3695, no ground, taxi, Alpha 10 to the ring.
Alpha 10 to the ring.
American 1370, at Whiskey, you're going to follow UPS, and monitor tower with David Lima.
We have the American 1370.
United 1080, Bravo service killer with the taxi, with Lima.
United 1080, we're going to try to whiskey, taxi via Julia.
Follow American at Romeo, and monitor tower with David Lima.
And Julia, it's brought me on follow American 1380.
So across the border here, Canada, 547, approaching Alpha 8.
We have Lima.
10 to the right, 47, no ground, taxi to the Whiskey, taxi via Bravo and Romeo.
2 to Bravo, Romeo to the Whiskey.
2 to the right, okay, okay, okay, okay.
547, meet your touch, meet your right, full line.
So turn left on Alpha, Sierra, and whole short of Yankee.
So turn left on Alpha, Sierra, whole short of Yankee.
We'll let you see right there.
And who's number two at Alpha 8?
9 to 14, 65, Lima.
So grab me at 2070, let's see if we can race.
We have golf going over here like today.
And 26 to the 7 to the ground, taxi, Alpha to the right.
Alpha, right behind 26 systems.
1465, no ground, we can try to whiskey, taxi via Bravo and Romeo.
If you're at whiskey, Bravo, Romeo, you have 1465.
You have 1465, whole short of Julia for volume over weight.
Okay, well, whole short of Julia, you have 1465.
I can at 547, continue on Sierra, Whiskey, go back and whole short of runway 11.
If you're Sierra, Whiskey, go back and whole short of runway 11.
2565, no ground, push back, approve, tail to the west.
Tail west, push crew.
Area 35, signature, taxi, pressure pass.
Area 35, no ground, taxi to the post depend.
We're going to call the tower 1838, this is Lima.
We've got Lima, 1883, once in there.
Area 35, right.
United, 18, 18.
South of Georgia, Bravo.
We have an animation playback.
This is United, 18, 18, no ground, runway.
Is it 18, 18, anything?
I don't care, that's right, 1-8, 1-8.
1-8, 18, 18, no ground, push out of Whiskey, taxi via Keyville, Sierra, whole short of unity for restriction over normal.
All right, that's Camilo, Sierra, and whole short of Whiskey versus who right at Whiskey.
Short of unity, please.
Sorry about that.
Whole short of Yankee.
United, out of 3-18.
Canada, 547 on, come back, cross only 11 and continue via Zulu.
Come back, cross only 11 and continue via Zulu.
Right there.
And there, Canada, 547 on Zulu.
You can now switch to the tower with 8 is Lima.
Okay, let's do this, switch to the tower, AOC, by our Canada, I'll talk with you.
1775, short of alpha-8 information.
We know.
Market 1575, North Carolina.
We're going to try to Whiskey, taxi via Bravo and Romeo.
Silver Romeo, 2-3, right Whiskey, American.
1575.
Good morning, United, 1980, for Romeo's Fox approaching alpha information, Lima.
We've got 1984, North Carolina.
We're going to try to Whiskey, taxi via Alpha, Sierra, and whole short of Keel.
Alpha, Sierra, short of Keel.
Thank you, too.
For a few, two, right, that was Whiskey.
1465, Virginia, Shreda, head to Whiskey.
And Monica, tower with 8 is Lima.
Okay, we'll put you straight ahead to Whiskey.
And over the tower, we have Lima.
2143, heavy, Bravo, short of Keel with Lima.
2143, heavy, North Carolina.
To try to Whiskey, taxi via Keel, and at Romeo, follow company.
Keel, Romeo, follow company.
2143, heavy.
2143, heavy, Monica, tower with 8 is Lima.
Have Lima, go on a tower, United, 2143, heavy, close.
Market 1575, full short of Julia.
Full short of Julia, fire.
1575.
Market 1575, follow the heavy, 16, yellow.
Fire.
And I'm sorry, yeah, move up to Keel, follow the heavy, and monitor tower with 8 is Lima.
All right, follow the heavy, Keel, and about our tower.
All right.
We've got to leave the American 1575.
Third ground up for the 421 heavy, Alpha Alpha, old sort of Alpha, old sort of Alpha.
FedEx 421, heavy, North Carolina.
To try to Whiskey, taxi via Bravo, and Romeo.
You read it with me via Bravo, Romeo.
United, 1818, turn right on to Yankee.
Have Romeo follow American, and monitor tower with 8 is Lima.
Right, that's right.
Yankee, and follow American on Romeo for United, 1818, and over the tower.
Third ground, yeah, I've collected 28 Lima, 300, shout out for 8.
Ready, taxi to Lima.
1428, do a crown.
We try to Whiskey, taxi via Bravo, and Bravo and Romeo.
Bravo, Romeo is a two-covada Whiskey, 940 and 28.
United, 1984, turn right on Keelo, short of Romeo.
Keelo, short of Romeo, United, 1884.
Bravo.